A Guide to the Laurance S. Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1009 FA452
Rockefeller Archive Center
Laurance S. Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1009
1911-1976
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller, Laurance Spelman
FA452
3 Cubic Feet Extent is approximate.
Approximately 50 prints
Arrangement
Rockefeller family photographic holdings are arranged into the following series: Rockefeller family and Avery family photographs, Series 1001. William Avery Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1002. John D. Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1003. William Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1004. John D. Rockefeller Jr. family photographs, Series 1005. Pocantico Hills photographs, Series 1006. John D. Rockefeller 3rd family photographs, Series 1007. Nelson A. Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1008. Laurance S. Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1009. David Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1010.
The Laurance S. Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1009, is futher arranged in subseries by format - Prints and Oversized.
Other Finding Aids
For other Rockefeller family photographic holdings, please see the following finding aids:
FA445 Rockefeller family and Avery family photographs, Series 1001
FA446 William Avery Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1002
FA447 John D. Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1003
FA448 William Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1004
FA449 John D. Rockefeller Jr. family photographs, Series 1005
FA450 Pocantico Hills photographs, Series 1006
FA451 John D. Rockefeller 3rd family photographs, Series 1007
FA454 Nelson A. Rockefeller photographs, Series 1008
FA453 David Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1010
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Scope and Contents
A small series of Laurance S. Rockefeller family photographs including portraits of Laurance S. Rockefeller as well as documention of a selection of his conservation and philanthropic activities including the Ramon Magsaysay Award Foundation, the Outdoor Recreation Resources Review Commission (ORRRC) and the Palasaides Interstate Park Commission.
Photographs
- Laurance S. Rockefeller family photographs, 1911-1976; 1009; Approximately 50 prints
  Arrangement
  For ease of access, the material is further arranged by:
  Prints (Boxes P 1, P 2, P 3, etc.). Oversized (Boxes: O 1, O 2, O 3, C 1, C 2, C 3, etc.).
  - Prints
    - Boat, 1 print (Box P 155)
    - Group Portraits - Family, 1953; 1 print (Box P 155)
      Scope and Contents
      Jackson Hole, WY
    - LSR - Business, 1941-1959; 2 prints (Box P 155)
    - LSR - Conservation - Outdoor Recreation Resource Review Commission (ORRRC), 1962 January; 10 prints (Box P 155)
      White House Meeting. President John F. Kennedy and Senator Henry Jackson are pictured in several images.
    - LSR - Miscellaneous, 1928; 1 print (Box P 155)
      Lincoln School, New York City
    - LSR - Philanthropies, 1950-1976; 3 prints (Box P 155)
      Memorial Sloan-Kettering Cancer Center (MSKCC) and Palisades Interstate Park Commission
    - LSR - Philanthropies - Ramon Magsaysay Award Foundation, 1959; 6 prints (Box P 155)
    - LSR - Portraits, 1911-1970s; 20 prints (Box P 155)
  - Oversized
    - LSR Portraits, 2 glass plate negatives only. (Box O 1)
      Conditions Governing Access
      Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
    - LSR - Philanthropies, 1 print (Box C 6)